Konstantin Gredeskoul

CTO / VPE / Principal Engineer / Tech Leader

Info

Address

San Francisco

Email

kigster@gmail.com

Skills

Ruby & Rails

.

PostgreSQL

• • • •

BASH

• • • •

SOLID OO Design

• • • •

DevOps

• • • • •

 C_{\cdot}/C_{++}

.

Bazel

• • • •

JavaScript

• • • •

lava

• • • • •

• • • •

Golang

• • • • •

Links

Blog

MakeABox.io

Github

LinkedIn

Presentations

Hobbies

Drums, Guitar, Piano, Keyboards DJ, & Electronic Music Producer as "PolyGroovers" (original music) and as "LeftCtrl" (DJ sets) on SoundCloud.

Profile

Konstantin is an avid ruby expert, and a four-times CTO who fell in love with Ruby in 2006. Since then he built two large e-commerce sites, and two socially connected e-commerce marketplaces, one of which (Wanelo.com) reached peak traffic of 250,000 RPMs with an average latency of 80ms. Konstantin has a passion for building well-oiled engineering teams from diverse backgrounds that harness the incredible power of pair-programming, TDD, collaborative software designs, infrastructure automation, and continuous deployment. He authored over forty open source ruby gems, and is fluent in Ruby, C/C++, Java and BASH (learning Go now). His gems have been downloaded nearly 20M times and his Slideshare Talks have been watched by over 250K people worldwide. He spoke at conference on using object stores and lambda functions to do high scale event collection and analytics, to scaling web applications atop of PostgreSQL RDBMS, to building efficient teams, to iterative development of enterprise software using Ruby. He is a passionate, creative, intuitive thinker, who infects others with enthusiasm, inspires mastery, while getting stuff done along the way

Employment History

Senior Software Engineer, Coinbase

Jun 2019 — Jan 2020

San Francisco

Extended the Bazel Build System using Starlark programming language (a subset of Python) to support Ruby language. The resulting open source project is available here: https://github.com/bazelruby/rules_ruby

Infrastructure Automation, Flow Tech Services

Nov 2018 − May 2019 San Francisco

Introduced Chef Enterprise on AWS, and following all security guidelines I was responsible for provisioning multiple environments (dev, staging, production) on EC2. Deployed on Ubuntu nodes with MRI Ruby built with jemalloc, deployed using Capistrano, registered Ruby's services such as Puma and Sidekiq as SystemD services, installed and configured Nginx, Haproxy, Redis and Memcached, while using PostgreSQL on RDS. Setup a secure (VPN-only), resilient and fault-tolerant infrastructure using Haproxy and DNS failover to handle failures. Besides working on the infrastructure, I introduced the engineering team to the XP Agile Process with points estimation, and led the first few planners. The process was adopted and resulted in better communication and faster feature delivery.

Lead Infrastructure Architect, Homebase, Inc.

Aug 2017 − Nov 2018 San Francisco

Revamped Homebase's systems architecture for the next generation of scale. I joined the team initially as a contractor, and then, after a couple of months, as a full-time employee, to work on addressing the performance issues and growing pains Homebase was going through at the time. I was able to introduce a number of significant performance improvements, reaching ptime of 99.99% in only a couple of months. I accomplished this by introducing multiple PostgreSQL replicas and distributing the app load across them, as well as rebuilding the infrastructure using Chef Enterprise and Docker on Ubuntu, wrangling AWS services such as RDS, S3, SNS, and EC2, optimizing our Ruby, Rails stack to work well with Redis, PostgreSQL and Memcached, all while deploying many times daily with Capistrano. Also responsible for reducing CI build times by 2X with CircleCI, and Docker-based parallelism. Built out the developer tooling (setup, secrets encryption, deployment) in the (nearly object- oriented) BASH v4, while open-sourcing the core library at https://github.com/kigster/bashmatic

CTO, Wanelo, Inc.

Mar 2012 − Nov 2016 San Francisco

I joined the company right after the Founder raised the seed round.

Working at two jobs for a couple of weeks, I jumped into fixing site's continuous outages caused by its own popularity and lack of performance-oriented thinking in the first prototype code-base. After applying sufficient amount of "duct tape" allowed the company a few months of breathing room, I focused on establishing high-performance engineering practices within the newly formed team. Closely following the Pivotal Process, my team agreed to try full-time pair-programming, in addition to more familiar practices of continuous integration, daily deployments, and TDD. In just under two months that followed, with the team of six, we replaced the old Java app – 90K lines of code, no tests – with a compact Rails app – 10K LOC including tests. We then brought live the new application, migrated data from MySQL to PostgreSQL, and swapped Cloud vendors all at the same time. With just one hour of planned maintenance. Full story: http://bit.ly/building-wanelo

CTO | Architect, Various

Apr 1998 − Mar 2012 San Francisco

Various leadership and engineering jobs in San Francisco. Details available by request.

Education

Monash Universty, Bachelor of Science

Honors Roll, Deans Excellence List (two years in a row), Statistical Society of Australia Study Scholarship, Winner of Prestigious SSA Award.

Kharkov State University, First Year, BSc

Mathematics and Advanced Calculus

References

Matt Camuto, Senior Software Engineer

I have worked with Konstantin and can say he is bar-none the most technically minded CTO and leader I have worker with. He has an amazing depth in system turning, scaling architectures and ruby programming and database tuning. His biggest contribution though was building a super well oiled engineering team that is the dictionary definition of efficient, lean and driving a fully automated deployment infrastructure and enforcing best practices such as TDD in a pairing environment. Overall Konstantin is a very passionate and creative technologist and a leader and would be a great asset to any team that wants to build an amazing tech organization. I would work with him again in a heart beat.

Adam Medeiros, Engineering Manager

Not only is Konstantin a Ruby Expert - that goes without saying - he is a great team leader. He takes the right risks, is willing to listen to other's point of view, and encourages advancement and progress of the individuals on his team. He really stays on top of where the Rails Community is going as well - and is a go-to guy if you need a suggestion on which tools are the right ones to use. Because of this we saw tremendous speed and performance improvements in our production environment and a clear path to a better development environment as well. It was an absolute pleasure working with him and I hope to do it again.